cscc.edu 2019-11-29

# Privacy Statement | Columbus State Community College

Thank you for visiting the Columbus State Community College Website and reviewing our privacy statement. Columbus State Community College does not collect personal information about visitors to our Website unless you choose to provide that information to us. Columbus State Community College does not sell, exchange or release information gathered from your visit to our web site to parties outside the college without your consent or when the conditions in this statement apply. You may opt out of email marketing communications by clicking the “unsubscribe” link. 

## Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If you visit our Website, the college automatically gathers and stores the following information about your visit so that we can track the use of our Website in order to make improvements. This information is stored and used in the aggregate only, and is not used to contact you personally: 

  * The IP address from which you access our Website
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, aol.com, if you are connecting from an America Online account) 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our Website
  * The date and time you access our site
  * The pages, files, documents and links that you visit
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked to this Website

### Cookies

In addition to information collected automatically, we may also collect cookies, which are small pieces of information sent to your browser by a website that you visit. Cookies are used to track usage patterns, traffic trends and customer behavior, as well as to record other information from the Website. Many content adjustments and customer service improvements are made based on the data derived from cookies. Information that we collect from cookies will not be used to create profiles of users and only will be used in aggregate form. 

You may set your browser to refuse cookies from any website that you visit. If you so choose, you may still gain access to most of the college's Website, but you may not be able to take advantage of some of the interactive elements offered. 

### If You Send Us Personal Information

The Columbus State Community College Website will collect personal information which you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, sending emails, requesting information, completing membership forms, registering for classes, events or other programs, responding to surveys or ordering merchandise. If you provide us with personal information, our process is to respond to your inquiry, request or order. We may also contact you to provide information about college activities, programs, membership and development opportunities and special events that may interest you. 

Columbus State Community College will share information about you to other parties when one or more of the following conditions apply: 

  * We have your consent to share the information.
  * We need to share your information to provide the service or product you requested.
  * We need to send your information to companies who work on behalf of Columbus State Community College to provide a service or product. 
  * We need to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or any other legal process.
  * We find it necessary to protect and defend the legal rights and/or property of Columbus State Community College. 

Student “directory information” may be released without the student’s written consent. Directory information at Columbus State includes: name, address, student.cscc.edu email address, telephone number, program of study, participation in Columbus State activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, enrollment status or dates of attendance at Columbus State, degrees, certificates and awards received, and the most recent previous educational institution attended. If you do not want your directory information released, you must complete a form requesting it not be released and file the form with [The Office of the Registrar](https://www.cscc.edu/services/registrar/withhold-information.shtml). 

### Information Security

Columbus State maintains an active Information Security program which monitors and responds to threats. The program verifies that implemented administrative and technical safeguards are operationally adequate, maintains quality control over security features and compliance and alerts the college community of threats. 

### Linking

Within our website there are links to non-Columbus State Websites. When you link to third party Websites, you leave our Website and no longer will be subject to our privacy statement. Columbus State community is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-Columbus State websites, and such link is not intended to be an endorsement of the non-Columbus State website or its content. 

### Comments

Columbus State Community College is a large organization with many people sharing responsibility for the content of our Website. Please help us respond to your comments and inquiries by sending them to the appropriate Columbus State Department. If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us via email at [news@cscc.edu](mailto:news@cscc.edu).
